Finding Aid for Kenneth P. Davis papers, 1930-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kenneth P. Davis papers 1930-1974
Davis, Kenneth P. (Kenneth Pickett), 1906-
85543 Aa 2
Educator and forester; correspondence, articles, reports, consulting files, and printed material concerning interests in forest management, forest fire control, use planning, forestry education, and participation in several land use lawsuits, including suit on the multiple use plan for Sylvania area, Ottawa National Forest; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
35 linear feet
The collection was the gift of Kenneth P. Davis (donor no. 5527 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Kenneth P. Davis was born September 2, 1906 in Denver Colorado. He received his B.S.F. degree from Montana State University in 1928, then worked as a forest ranger with the U.S. Forest Service from 1928 to 1931. He returned to school receiving his master's degree from the University of Michigan in 1932. From 1933 to 1933, he was a silviculture researcher with the Northern Rocky Mountain Forest and Range Experiment Station. In 1940, he received his doctorate from the University of Michigan. From 1940 to 1943, he was assistant chief in the division of forest management research of the U.S. Forest Service in Washington, D.C. He was chief of the division 1944-1945.
In 1945 Davis was appointed dean of the School of Forestry at Montana State University, a position he held until 1949, when he returned to the University of Michigan as professor of forest management. He was appointed chairman of the forestry department in 1950. In 1965 Davis was made acting dean of the School of Natural Resources, and served in that position for one year until a permanent dean was chosen. He remained at the U-M until 1967 when he became professor of forest land use at Yale School of Forestry.
Davis held high positions in the Society of American Foresters, as council member, vice-president, and president. He was also a member of the Michigan State Board of Registration of Foresters. Davis died on November 29, 1982.
The Davis collection documents his various activities as a teacher, consultant, and practicing forester. The collection has been arranged into the following series: Biographical / Personal; Correspondence; Writings; University of Michigan Student, 1932-1933; University of Michigan Faculty, 1949-1966; Yale University Faculty, 1967-1974; Society of American Foresters; Conferences and Programs attended; International Forestry; Consulting File; Forest Management; Forest Cutting Practices Study, 1944-1957; Continuous Forest Inventory Study, 1959-1960; Nashwaak Pulp and Paper Company Case, New Brunswick, 1967-1972; Other topics; Photographs.
Subjects:
Forest fires--United States.; Forests and forestry--United States.; Land use--United States.; Michigan. State Board of Registration for Foresters.; Ottawa National Forest (Mich.); Society of American Foresters.; Sylvania Recreation Area (Mich.); United States. Forest Service.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Forestry.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.; Yale University.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Camping.; Davis, Kenneth P. (Kenneth Pickett), 1906-; Forest fires--United States.; Forestry.; Idaho.; Sylvania Recreation Area (Mich.); University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.; Winter.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Biographical / Personal
  - Personnel file (appointments, etc.), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Genealogy (Box 1)
  - Diary 1941-1959 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1930-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1943 (re. publication of his thesis) (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945 (Box 1)
  - 1945 (re. University of Montana) (Box 1)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (re. University of Michigan) (Box 1)
  - 1950-1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1963 (Box 1)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (re. U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization) (Box 1)
  - 1966 (re. Yale University) (Box 1)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1968 (re. Ann Arbor) (Box 1)
  - January-June 1968 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1968 (Box 1)
  - June-September 1969 (Box 1)
  - October 1969-August 1970 (Box 1)
  - September 1970-June 1971 (Box 2)
  - July-December 1971 (Box 2)
  - January 1972-March 1973 (Box 2)
  - April 1973-May 1974 (Box 2)
  - George Banzhaf (Box 2)
  - David T. Mason (Box 2)
  - Stephen H. Spurr (Box 2)
  - Requests and Reviews 1967-1974 (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Manuscript Files, Published articles and speeches (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Files, Published articles and speeches (Box 3)
    (including audio of one speech)
  - Published papers and articles
    - 1935-1938 (Box 3)
    - 1939-1942 (Box 3)
    - 1943-1946 (Box 3)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 3)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 3)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1970 (Box 3)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Forest Management Book
    - Correspondence 1949-1961 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence 1961-1967 (Box 4)
  - Forest Fire Control Book
    - Correspondence
      - 1955-1959 (Box 4)
      - 1959-1965 (Box 4)
      - Chapter Review (Box 4)
      - McGraw-Hill (Box 4)
      - R. Keith Arnold (Box 4)
      - Arthur W. Hartman (Box 4)
      - Michigan Department of Conservation (Box 4)
      - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 4)
      - U.S. Forest Service, 4 folders (Box 4)
      - A.A. Brown, 2 folders (Box 4)
- University of Michigan Student 1932-1933
  - Term papers
    - "Development of Federal Acquisition and Exchange Policy" (Box 5)
    - "Survey of Commercial Forestry" (Box 5)
    - "Sustained Yield vs. Destructive Logging" (Box 5)
    - "Pathological Study of an Eastern Michigan Farm Woodlot" (Box 5)
    - "Public Control of Private Forestry" (Box 5)
    - "Federal Money in Private Business" (Box 5)
  - Forest Management notes, 10 folders (Box 5)
- University of Michigan Faculty 1949-1966
  - General Education, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - General Conservation (Box 5)
  - Short Course papers
    - Technical writing, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Technical writing, 1 folders (Box 6)
    - Control of the Managed Forest, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Seminar on teaching (Box 6)
  - Forestry 482, Notes and Examinations, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Forestry 584, Notes and Examinations, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Forestry 295 and 595, Notes and Examinations, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Lectures given at University of Helsinki 1963, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Yale University Faculty 1967-1974
  - General Education, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - School of Forestry (Box 7)
  - Forestry Course Evaluations (Box 7)
  - Wood Science Committee (Box 7)
  - Resource Management Committee (Box 7)
  - Informal Faculty Dinners (Box 7)
  - Institute of Social Science (Box 7)
  - Forestry Seminar Speakers
    - Kenneth R. Andrews (Box 7)
    - Michael Frome (Box 7)
    - Dennis Rapp (Box 7)
  - Forestry 102a, Notes and Examinations, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Industrial Forestry Seminar (Box 7)
  - SAF Forestry Education Seminar (Box 8)
  - Forest Biology Training Session, University of Minnesota (Box 8)
  - Commission on Education in Agriculture and Natural Resources (Box 8)
  - The Professional School and World Affairs Conference (Box 8)
- Society of American Foresters, 1939-1971
  - General 1939-1970
    - Papers 1951-1966 (Box 8)
    - Davis Candidacy for President 1964-1965 (Box 8)
    - Davis Candidacy for Vice-President 1967 (Box 8)
    - SAF Council
      - 1957-1958 (Box 8)
      - 1959 (Box 8)
      - 1960 (Box 8)
      - 1961 (Box 8)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 8)
      - 1967 (Box 8)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - Annual Meeting 1965 (Box 9)
    - SAF Council Meeting
      - September 1966 (Box 9)
      - May 1967 (Box 9)
      - October 1967 (Box 9)
      - March 1968 (Box 9)
      - September-October 1968, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - April 1969 (Box 9)
      - October 1969 (Box 9)
    - Finance
      - 1965-1966, General (Box 9)
      - 1966, Committee papers (Box 9)
      - 1966, Dues increase (Box 9)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 9)
      - 1969 (Box 9)
    - Insurance Plan
      - 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - 1968 (Box 10)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 10)
      - 1969 (Box 10)
    - Silviculture Division 1946-1952 (Box 10)
    - Education Division
      - 1946 (Box 10)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 10)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 10)
    - Forest Fire division (proposed) 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - Forest Terminology subcommittee 1939 (Box 10)
    - Committee on Objectives 1946 (Box 10)
    - Interview and Personnel Records committee 1949 (Box 10)
    - Biologist Award 1957-1960 (Box 10)
    - Cubic Foot Standardization committee 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - Policy Committee 1961 (Box 10)
    - Visiting Scientist program
      - 1961-1962 (Box 10)
      - 1962-1966 (Box 10)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 10)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 10)
    - Wisconsin-Michigan Section
      - 1958-1966, General (Box 10)
      - 1961-1963, Chairman file (Box 10)
    - Central States Section 1958-1961 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous Sections 1967 (Box 10)
    - New England Section 1967-1969 (Box 10)
    - Lower Michigan Chapter 1954-1966 (Box 10)
    - Lower Michigan Chapter, Forest Practices committee 1956 (Box 10)
  - Kenneth Davis Presidency 1970-1971
    - SAF Data Book (Box 11)
    - SAF Manual (Box 11)
    - SAF Committees (Box 11)
    - Constitution and Historical material (Box 11)
    - Council minutes 1965-1971 (Box 11)
    - Davis candidacy for president 1970 (Box 11)
    - Policy statements, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Policy position, Big Thicket (Box 11)
    - Correspondence with H.R. Glascock, Jr. (Box 11)
    - President's file-
      - Correspondence and memos 1970, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Correspondence and memos 1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - SAF Council Affairs 1970 (Box 12)
    - SAF Council Meeting
      - April 1970 (Box 12)
      - October 1970, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - April 1971 (Box 12)
      - July 1971 (Box 12)
      - September 1971 (Box 12)
      - November 1971 (Box 12)
      - 1973 (Box 12)
    - SAF Committees-Roster of candidates (Box 12)
    - Accreditation policy (Box 12)
    - Ethics cases, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - SAF Division Reorganization, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Land Use Committee, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Fund raising (Box 13)
    - Dues increase (Box 13)
    - Task force on member recruitment (Box 13)
    - Forestry education, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Biologist award (Box 13)
    - Pinchot and Schlich awards (Box 13)
    - Journal of Forestry Regional Insert question (Box 13)
    - Special Interest files
      - Boy Scouts (Box 13)
      - Editorial Advisory Board-Forest Science (Box 13)
      - Membership (Box 13)
      - Insurance (Box 13)
      - Miscellanea (Box 13)
      - Inter-Agency Cooperation (Box 13)
      - Fort Gordon, Ga.-Forestry Personnel (Box 13)
      - National Conference on Forest, Weather, and Associated Environment (Box 13)
      - Professional programs (Box 13)
      - Forester registration (Box 13)
    - New England Section 1969-1974 (Box 13)
    - Section meetings 1969-1971 (Box 13)
    - Michigan State Board of Registration for Foresters 1956-1962 (Box 13)
- Conferences and Programs attended
  - Informal talks and speeches
    - 1938-1940 (Box 13)
    - 1945-1951 (Box 13)
    - 1954-1959 (Box 14)
    - 1967-1974 (Box 14)
  - Joint Investigative Council 1938 (Box 14)
  - American Forestry Association 1950 (Box 14)
  - American Forestry Congress 1953 (Box 14)
  - Forestry School Deans 1956 (Box 14)
  - Southern States Fire Control Conference 1957 (Box 14)
  - American Pulpwood Association 1957 (Box 14)
  - Growth and Cut Symposium 1959 (Box 14)
  - Forestry School Deans 1960 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Conference on International Development 1960, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Southern Pulpwood Conservation Association 1961 (Box 14)
  - Lake States Forest Fire Research conference 1961 (Box 14)
  - Fire Research Committee 1961 (Box 14)
  - Lake States Council of Industrial Foresters 1962 (Box 14)
  - National Conference on Professional Education for Outdoor (Box 14)
  - Recreation 1964 (Box 14)
  - Continuous Forest Inventory 1965 (Box 14)
  - Conference on Education in Renewable Natural Resources 1967 (Box 14)
  - Western trip 1967 (Box 14)
  - Washington, D.C. trips 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - Chamber of Commerce of Quebec 1968 (Box 14)
  - Milwaukee trip 1968 (Box 14)
  - International Paper Co., Southlands Experimental Forest 1969 (Box 14)
  - Conference on Multiple Use of Southern Forests 1969 (Box 14)
  - National Association of State Foresters 1970 (Box 14)
  - Washington, D.C. trip 1970 (Box 14)
  - U.S. Timber Supply National Policy Conference 1970 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Forest Service Supervisors Meeting 1970 (Box 15)
  - University of Toronto, Weyerhauser Lecture 1971 (Box 15)
  - Upper Mississippi Valley Section, SAF 1971 (Box 15)
  - Northern Rocky Mountain Section, SAF 1972 (Box 15)
  - Auburn Forestry Forum 1972 (Box 15)
  - University of Michigan, Natural Resources Distinguished (Box 15)
  - Alumni 1972 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1940-1951 (Box 15)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 15)
    - 1954-1959 (Box 15)
    - 1960-1966 (Box 15)
    - 1966-1974 (Box 15)
- International Forestry
  - General 1951-1971, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Fifth World Forestry Congress 1960
    - General (Box 16)
    - Papers (Box 16)
    - Program committee (Box 16)
  - Tenth Pacific Science Congress 1961
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Programs (Box 16)
    - Papers (Box 16)
  - Trip to Europe 1963
    - Correspondence and notes, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - Forestry education (Box 16)
    - Fulbright grant (Box 16)
  - Sixth World Forestry Congress 1966
    - Correspondence and notes (Box 17)
    - General (Box 17)
    - Forest management and planning (Box 17)
    - Forest administration and policy, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Forest workers (Box 17)
    - Tropical forestry, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Forest economics and finance (Box 17)
  - International Union of Societies of Foresters Papers 1968-1971 (Box 17)
  - International Forestry Committee Correspondence 1970 (Box 17)
  - International Union of Forestry Research Organizations
    - Correspondence 1970-1973 (Box 17)
    - Fifteenth Congress 1971, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - United Nations Conference on the Environment Papers 1972 (Box 17)
- Consulting File
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1957-1971 (Box 18)
  - National Science Foundation-University of Washington proposal 1971 (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Science and Technology study 1971-1972
    - Forest Service FALCON Project (Box 18)
    - National Disasters (Box 18)
  - McGraw Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology 1961-1971 (Box 18)
  - U.S. Forest Service Timber Management Review Board 1962
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Reference materials, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Hearings (Box 18)
  - Union Bag-Camp Paper Corporation 1966
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Report (Box 18)
    - Notes, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Annual reports and operating manuals, 11 folders (Box 18)
  - Southern Forest Industry 1972 (Box 19)
  - Georgia Forestry Commission 1956-1959
    - Forest Fire control (Box 19)
    - Reorganization, 6 folders (Box 19)
  - University of Georgia Forestry School 1956, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Kirby Lumber Company 1958-1960 (Box 19)
  - Celotex Corporation 1961 (Box 19)
  - Owens-Illinois 1960 (Box 19)
  - Battelle Memorial Institute 1957 (Box 19)
  - Kimberly Clark 1972 (Box 19)
- Forest Management
  - Correspondence 1947-1967, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous reports, notes, and newsletters 1950-1972, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous reports, notes, and newsletters 1950-1972, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - U.S. Forest Service Management Manuals 1960-1966, 7 folders (Box 20)
  - Allowable cut 1949-1970, 6 folders (Box 20)
  - Silviculture 1934-1959 (Box 20)
  - Timber Sale contracts 1965-1970 (Box 20)
  - Social legislation and forestry 1950-1958 (Box 20)
  - Coop Sustained Yield Units 1949-1964, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Unit Area Control 1956-1963 (Box 21)
  - Logging and Milling 1946-1952 (Box 21)
  - Spacing 1950-1951 (Box 21)
  - Blister Rust Control 1946-1948 (Box 21)
  - Puerto Rico 1959 (Box 21)
  - Michigan 1949-1950 (Box 21)
  - West Virginia Pulp and Paper Co- 1959-1960 (Box 21)
- Forest Cutting Practices Study 1944-1957
  - General, 5 folders (Box 21)
  - U.S. Forest Service Forest Practice Committee 1944-1946 General
    - Region 1 (Box 21)
    - Region 2 (Box 21)
    - Region 3 (Box 21)
    - Region 4 (Box 21)
    - Region 5 (Box 21)
    - Region 6 (Box 21)
    - Region 7 (Box 21)
    - Region 8 (Box 21)
    - Region 9 (Box 21)
  - Society of American Foresters Forest Practice Committee 1945-1957
    - Reports, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - 1945-1946 (Box 21)
      - 1947 (Box 21)
      - 1950-1957 (Box 21)
      - SAF Headquarters (Box 21)
      - Committee members (Box 21)
      - George Amidon (Box 22)
      - W.S. Bromley (Box 22)
      - C.E. Farnsworth (Box 22)
      - Russell LeBarron (Box 22)
      - H.H. Muntz (Box 22)
      - Ken Pomeroy (Box 22)
      - C.W. Richen (Box 22)
      - Allegheny Section (Box 22)
      - Appalachian Section (Box 22)
      - Central States Section (Box 22)
      - Inland Empire Section (Box 22)
      - New England Section (Box 22)
      - New York, Gulf States, Intermountain, Southwestern Sections (Box 22)
      - Minnesota Section (Box 22)
      - Puget Sound Section (Box 22)
      - Southeastern Section (Box 22)
      - Wisconsin-Upper Michigan Section (Box 22)
      - Lower Michigan Section (Box 22)
  - State Forest Practices
    - California (Box 22)
    - Florida (Box 22)
    - Idaho (Box 22)
    - Maryland (Box 22)
    - Massachusetts (Box 22)
    - Minnesota (Box 22)
    - Mississippi (Box 22)
    - Missouri (Box 22)
    - New Hampshire (Box 22)
    - New Mexico (Box 22)
    - New York (Box 22)
    - Oregon (Box 22)
    - Vermont (Box 22)
    - Virginia (Box 22)
    - Washington (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 22)
- Continuous Forest Inventory Study 1959-1960
  - General-Plans, etc. (Box 23)
  - Travel funds (Box 23)
  - Itinerary (Box 23)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Box 23)
    - Southeast (Box 23)
    - Lake States (Box 23)
    - Deep South (Box 23)
    - West (Box 23)
  - Preliminary correspondence and memos, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Publications, bibliography, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Sample flow charts and plat grids (Box 23)
  - Short course, University of Georgia 1959, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Conference, Purdue University 1960, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Enso-Gutzeit Co. (Finland) (Box 23)
  - Conference, Milwaukee 1953 (Box 23)
  - Conference, Houghton 1965 (Box 23)
  - Forestry 384, paper by G.P. Juan (Box 23)
  - Lake States
    - Celotex Corporation (Box 23)
    - Kimberly-Clark Corporation, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Cleveland Cliffs Iron Company (Box 23)
    - Minnesota and Ontario Paper Company, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Rhinelander Paper Company (Box 24)
    - State of Wisconsin, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - U.S. Forest Service Region 9 (Box 24)
    - Menominee Indian Reservation (Box 24)
    - Michigan Conservation Department (Box 24)
    - Nekoosa-Edwards Paper Company (Box 24)
    - Marathon Corporation (Box 24)
  - South
    - Bowaters Southern Paper Corporation (Box 24)
    - Buckeye Cellulose Corporation (Box 24)
    - Crossett Lumber Company (Box 24)
    - Clemson College Forest (Box 24)
    - Container Corporation of America (Box 24)
    - Gaylord Container Corporation (Box 24)
    - Georgia Kraft Company, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - International Paper Company (Box 24)
    - T.L. James Company (Box 24)
    - Owens-Illinois Glass Company (Box 24)
    - Kirby Lumber Company (Box 24)
    - Olin Mathieson Chemical Corporation (Box 24)
    - Union Bag-Camp Paper Corporation (Box 24)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 25)
    - West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company (Box 25)
    - St. Regis Paper Company (Box 25)
    - U.S. Forest Service Region 8 (Box 25)
  - West
    - Southern Pacific Company (Box 25)
    - Crown Zellerbach Corporation (Box 25)
    - Weyerhauser Company, 3 folders (Box 25)
    - U.S. Forest Service
      - Region 4 (Box 25)
      - Region 5 (Box 25)
      - Region 6 (Box 25)
- Nashwaak Pulp and Paper Company Case, New Brunswick 1967-1972
  - Correspondence
    - March 1967-April 1969 (Box 26)
    - May 1969-December 1969 (Box 26)
    - January 1970-July 1972 (Box 26)
  - Personal notes (Box 26)
  - Valuation report papers, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Mactaquac Regional Development Plan (Box 26)
  - Land Transactional Data
    - Oxford paper company, 9 folders (Box 26)
    - Provincial government, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Interviews (Box 26)
  - Technical data
    - Inventory (Box 26)
    - Growth, 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Stumpage (Box 26)
    - Cut and Mill Use, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - General data: Forest Industry Studies, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Hearings
    - Trial notes, 8 folders (Box 27)
    - Provincial orders (Box 27)
    - Transcripts, 12 folders (Box 27)
- Other topics
  - Small Owner Forestry 1949-1964, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Land Use Planning 1966-1974
    - General, 6 folders (Box 28)
    - Special aspects, 7 folders (Box 28)
    - Federal legislation, 7 folders (Box 28)
    - U.S. Forest Service, 4 folders (Box 28)
    - New England, 14 folders (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, 7 folders (Box 29)
  - Absaroka Beartooth Wilderness Proposal (Mont.) 1974 (Box 29)
  - Recreation Carrying Capacity 1972 (Box 29)
  - U.S. Forest Service Multiple Use Planning 1960-1973, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - U.S. Forest Service Multiple Use Planning 1960-1973, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Bureau of Land Management Multiple Use Planning 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - U.S. Forest Service Magruder Corridor Study Committee.(Idaho) 1966-1967
    - Correspondence and notes, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Forest Service plans, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Surveys and evaluations, 7 folders (Box 30)
    - Hearing transcripts, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Working papers (Box 30)
    - Report development (Box 30)
    - Reaction to committee report (Box 30)
    - Subsequent action (Box 30)
    - Case materials (Box 30)
  - U.S. Forest Service Sylvania Case (Mich.) 1966-1969, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - U.S. Forest Service East Meadow Creek Case (Colo.) 1969-1972, 6 folders (Box 31)
  - U.S. Forest Service Clearcutting controversy 1970-1972, 8 folders (Box 31)
  - Public Land Law Review Commission 1967-1970, 4 folders (Box 32)
  - Lake Tahoe Regional Plan study 1968-1972, 6 folders (Box 32)
  - Forest Taxation 1955-1966 (Box 33)
    - Property tax, 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Income tax, 4 folders (Box 33)
    - General, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Forest Financial management 1940-1973
    - Programming (Box 33)
    - Resource Valuation, 3 folders (Box 33)
    - Decision making, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Forest Statistics Course materials 1936 (Box 34)
  - Forest Economics and National Policy 1938-1952, 5 folders (Box 34)
  - Administrative Management 1939-1958, 5 folders (Box 34)
  - Forestry Publicity, Radio-T.V. 1947-1964, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Forest Fire Equipment 1951 (Box 34)
  - Trail Riders of the Wilderness-Quetico Superior Region 1951-1954 (Box 34)
  - Winter Snowshoe trip 1962 (Box 34)
  - U.S. Forest Service Training Guides 1962-1963 (Box 34)
  - Planning-Programming-Budgeting System 1965-1969, 2 folders (Box 34)
- Photographs
  - Records of photographs. Includes Forest Service photographic record from Idaho (Box 35)
    (Note: Not all photos described in this folder have been retained)
  - Cultural treatments
    - Fire (Box 35)
    - General (Box 35)
    - Hardwood girdling, and poisoning of understory vegetation in the South (Box 35)